<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.readfence.Readfence</id>

  <name>Readfence</name>
  <summary>Clean, modern Markdown viewer</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <developer id="com.readfence">
    <name>SignalPeak Media LLC</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      Readfence is a clean, modern Markdown viewer built for developers and
      Linux users. It renders Markdown beautifully by default, with heading
      hierarchy, code blocks, inline code, bold, italic, links, and blockquotes.
    </p>
    <p>Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Rendered Markdown by default, with a toggleable raw source view</li>
      <li>Selectable rendered text you can highlight and copy across headings, paragraphs, lists, quotes, and code blocks</li>
      <li>Reader-friendly code blocks with language labels and a one-click copy action</li>
      <li>A multi-file sidebar for opening and switching between documents</li>
      <li>Drag and drop to open Markdown or text files instantly</li>
      <li>Automatic reload when an open file changes on disk</li>
      <li>Fullscreen reading mode and adjustable font size</li>
      <li>A rich theme library including Dark, Light, Dracula, Nord, Gruvbox, Solarized, Tokyo Night, and Catppuccin</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.readfence.Readfence.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://readfence.com/screenshot.png</image>
      <caption>A Markdown document rendered in Readfence</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://readfence.com</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/adamwhiles/readfence/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/adamwhiles/readfence</url>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>TextEditor</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>Markdown</keyword>
    <keyword>md</keyword>
    <keyword>viewer</keyword>
    <keyword>reader</keyword>
    <keyword>preview</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>A full rendering overhaul, image support, curated themes, and update notifications.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Tables render as aligned columns with bold headers</li>
          <li>Inline bold, italic, code, and strikethrough styling now renders everywhere</li>
          <li>Lists get real bullets, correct nesting, task-list checkboxes, and accent markers</li>
          <li>Blockquotes and GitHub-style alerts get accent bars and labels</li>
          <li>Local and remote images render in place, including SVG badges</li>
          <li>Fifteen curated themes with polished light-mode support; your choice is remembered</li>
          <li>Responsive toolbar and refined application chrome</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.4" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Desktop integration and packaging improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Open files passed on the command line or via a file-manager "Open with" action</li>
          <li>Register a desktop entry and icon, and associate Markdown files with Readfence</li>
          <li>Initial Flatpak packaging</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.3" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>Rendering improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Reworked the Markdown rendering pipeline</li>
          <li>Improved the visual presentation of rendered documents</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
